ALVIN JUDE

nationality	Malaysian	email	alvin@dartarrow.net
d.o.b.	9 March 1984	website	http://dartarrow.net
residence	San Jose, CA	phone	(254) 413 1023

As a former DevOps, I enjoy working on the whole stack. My primary research interest lies is in the human factors of computer science; my masters thesis will be in the area of Human Computer Interaction, specifically involving accessibility with gestures. My goal is to make interaction easier at all levels, including the developer level. I strive to increase my breadth of knowledge, to allow me better understanding of the utilization of technology from both consumer and business perspective, while actively maintaining my deep technical roots.

I prefer the trees but I see the forest.

EDUCATION

Masters of Computer Science · 2012–Present · Baylor University

Specialization: Human Computer Interaction

THESIS: Giving the Users a Hand: Towards Touchless Hand Gestures for the Desktop

Bachelor of Computer Science · 2002–2005 · Coventry University

RANK: Honours, Second Class Upper

THESIS: Remote PC Manipulation via PDA over Bluetooth

PUBLICATIONS

Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness. 2014. *Personal Space: User Defined Gesture Space for GUI Interaction*. In CHI '14 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '14). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 1615-1620. DOI=10.1145/2559206.2581242 http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2559206.2581242

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Basic: R · Matlab · C# · Tomcat · HBase · JQuery · Css3 · HAProxy · Heartbeat · DRBD

 $\label{eq:lambdate:python} \textbf{IMTEX} \cdot \textbf{C} \cdot \textbf{PostgreSQL} \cdot \textbf{Nmap} \cdot \textbf{Git} \cdot \textbf{Hibernate} \cdot \textbf{Objective-C} \cdot \textbf{Memcached}$

 $\label{eq:advanced: NGinX · Puppet · Nagios · Collectd · PHP5 · MySQL · Java · Symfony · OpenVZ$

NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

COMMUNICATIONFormer Malaysian Public Speaking Champion

EntrepreneurshipBaylor NewVenture 2014: Top-5 Finalist & 3rd place Elevator Pitch

LanguagesEnglish · Native

Malay · Intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

Baylor University · 2013–Present · Research Assistant

Tasked to setup newly formed Human Computer Interaction lab. Mentored juniors, established engineering procedures and infrastructure. Performed research in Hand-Gestural interaction and explored research options with other next-generation devices. Reference: G. Michael Poor · michael poor@baylor.edu

· 2012–2013 · Teaching Assistant

On top of general TA duties, also introduced fixes and developer's manual to software used in-house for teaching databases.

Reference: Greg Speegle · greg_speegle@baylor.edu

Self Employed · 2010–2012 · Technical Consultant

Served as an independent consultant for various project and companies including the following:

· 2011–2012 · iOS Development, AGILE PERSPECTIVES — MALAYSIA

Developed iOS applications for an international insurance corporation, as well as one iOS app for a consumer-facing startup dealing in retail. Role included feasibility studies, technical consultation and R&D

· 2010–2011 · System Administration, CouchSurfing.org

Daily operations: monitoring, security, optimization, deployment, etc. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, HAProxy. Deployed a cluster of static content servers (NGinX) to reduce the load off the dynamic servers which resulted in much higher reliability.

Aflexi · 2009–2010 · System Engineer

Aflexi was a CDN Software startup, and is currently a division of OnApp. Responsibilities were more DevOps involving backend development and system administration. Accomplishmenst include building a monitoring infrastructure from the ground up (traditionally done with Nagios) with custom scripts running on a specialized Collectd infrastructurep; used to feed PowerDNS for DNS-based CDN routing. Tools of the trade also included Puppet, Zabbix, Nagios, Reprepro, RRD.

Reference: Whei Wong · whei.wong@onapp.com

iMocha Consulting · 2007–2010 · Team Lead

Initially hired as a Junior Java Developer, but quickly tasked to build and run a LAMP team of up to 8 people, dealing mostly with financial institutions. Responsibilities included hiring, firing, and mentoring programmers, system administrators, system analysts, and interns, as well as requirements gathering from clients.

Reference: Koh Kok Wei · kokwei@imocha.com.my

Sony Manufacturing · 2005–2007 · Engineer

Developed Linux-based software required for manufacturing. Developed a tool used to trace products which helped cut down tracability time from 2 working days to about 4 hours. Tools of the trade included MFC, VB.NET, PHP, Postgres, GTK.